1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,000
{\an5}m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8

2
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,000
{\an5}m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8

3
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,000
{\an5}{\pos(145,227)}m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8

4
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(67,223)}m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0

5
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(67,223)}m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35

6
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(58,213)}m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60

7
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(84,223)}m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172

10
00:00:06,000 --> 00:00:41,510
{\an9}m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1

11
00:00:05,500 --> 00:00:41,510
{\an2}{\pos(26,248)}m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1

22
00:00:46,520 --> 00:00:51,520
{\an8}{\pos(94.16,212.825)}app.YYeTs.com

23
00:00:41,520 --> 00:00:51,520
{\pos(38.183,216.492)}m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0

24
00:00:41,520 --> 00:00:51,520
{\pos(38.297,216.125)}m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35

25
00:00:41,520 --> 00:00:51,520
{\pos(36.709,216.297)}m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60

27
00:00:41,520 --> 00:00:51,520
{\an7}{\pos(17.28,184.189)} m 200 100 l 200 110 l 210 110 l 210 100 m 210 100 m 160 50 l 160 60 l 170 60 l 170 50 m 170 50 m 150 150 l 150 160 l 160 160 l 160 150 m 160 150 m 140 210 l 140 220 l 150 220 l 150 210 m 150 210 m 40 240 l 40 250 l 50 250 l 50 240 m 50 240 m 200 130 l 200 140 l 210 140 l 210 130 m 210 130 m 180 80 l 180 90 l 190 90 l 190 80 m 190 80 m 110 160 l 110 170 l 120 170 l 120 160 m 120 160 m 160 160 l 160 170 l 170 170 l 170 160 m 170 160 m 280 210 l 280 220 l 290 220 l 290 210 m 290 210 m 220 80 l 220 90 l 230 90 l 230 80 m 230 80 m 190 240 l 190 250 l 200 250 l 200 240 m 200 240 m 280 80 l 280 90 l 290 90 l 290 80 m 290 80 m 210 240 l 210 250 l 220 250 l 220 240 m 220 240 m 250 130 l 250 140 l 260 140 l 260 130 m 260 130 m 170 210 l 170 220 l 180 220 l 180 210 m 180 210 m 240 240 l 240 250 l 250 250 l 250 240 m 250 240 m 50 100 l 50 110 l 60 110 l 60 100 m 60 100 m 40 140 l 40 150 l 50 150 l 50 140 m 50 140 m 60 260 l 60 270 l 70 270 l 70 260 m 70 260 m 260 100 l 260 110 l 270 110 l 270 100 m 270 100 m 250 100 l 250 110 l 260 110 l 260 100 m 260 100 m 120 90 l 120 100 l 130 100 l 130 90 m 130 90 m 80 40 l 80 50 l 90 50 l 90 40 m 90 40 m 70 280 l 70 290 l 80 290 l 80 280 m 80 280 m 120 280 l 120 290 l 130 290 l 130 280 m 130 280 m 150 90 l 150 100 l 160 100 l 160 90 m 160 90 m 100 140 l 100 150 l 110 150 l 110 140 m 110 140 m 90 220 l 90 230 l 100 230 l 100 220 m 100 220 m 160 100 l 160 110 l 170 110 l 170 100 m 170 100 m 280 180 l 280 190 l 290 190 l 290 180 m 290 180 m 220 130 l 220 140 l 230 140 l 230 130 m 230 130 m 40 80 l 40 90 l 50 90 l 50 80 m 50 80 m 280 50 l 280 60 l 290 60 l 290 50 m 290 50 m 170 240 l 170 250 l 180 250 l 180 240 m 180 240 m 240 80 l 240 90 l 250 90 l 250 80 m 250 80 m 220 240 l 220 250 l 230 250 l 230 240 m 230 240 m 120 190 l 120 200 l 130 200 l 130 190 m 130 190 m 260 70 l 260 80 l 270 80 l 270 70 m 270 70 m 80 140 l 80 150 l 90 150 l 90 140 m 90 140 m 70 60 l 70 70 l 80 70 l 80 60 m 80 60 m 60 100 l 60 110 l 70 110 l 70 100 m 70 100 m 130 180 l 130 190 l 140 190 l 140 180 m 140 180 m 120 60 l 120 70 l 130 70 l 130 60 m 130 60 m 90 150 l 90 160 l 100 160 l 100 150 m 100 150 m 100 40 l 100 50 l 110 50 l 110 40 m 110 40 m 90 280 l 90 290 l 100 290 l 100 280 m 100 280 m 80 200 l 80 210 l 90 210 l 90 200 m 90 200 m 180 280 l 180 290 l 190 290 l 190 280 m 190 280 m 130 200 l 130 210 l 140 210 l 140 200 m 140 200 m 280 280 l 280 290 l 290 290 l 290 280 m 290 280 m 180 190 l 180 200 l 190 200 l 190 190 m 190 190 m 100 270 l 100 280 l 110 280 l 110 270 m 110 270 m 240 230 l 240 240 l 250 240 l 250 230 m 250 230 m 230 170 l 230 180 l 240 180 l 240 170 m 240 170 m 190 180 l 190 190 l 200 190 l 200 180 m 200 180 m 200 230 l 200 240 l 210 240 l 210 230 m 210 230 m 170 140 l 170 150 l 180 150 l 180 140 m 180 140 m 240 180 l 240 190 l 250 190 l 250 180 m 250 180 m 250 220 l 250 230 l 260 230 l 260 220 m 260 220 m 220 140 l 220 150 l 230 150 l 230 140 m 230 140 m 40 50 l 40 60 l 50 60 l 50 50 m 50 50 m 270 230 l 270 240 l 280 240 l 280 230 m 280 230 m 160 260 l 160 270 l 170 270 l 170 260 m 170 260 m 70 160 l 70 170 l 80 170 l 80 160 m 80 160 m 80 190 l 80 200 l 90 200 l 90 190 m 90 190 m 60 150 l 60 160 l 70 160 l 70 150 m 70 150 m 270 130 l 270 140 l 280 140 l 280 130 m 280 130 m 70 220 l 70 230 l 80 230 l 80 220 m 80 220 m 140 180 l 140 190 l 150 190 l 150 180 m 150 180 m 120 220 l 120 230 l 130 230 l 130 220 m 130 220 m 80 250 l 80 260 l 90 260 l 90 250 m 90 250 m 150 190 l 150 200 l 160 200 l 160 190 m 160 190 m 230 270 l 230 280 l 240 280 l 240 270 m 240 270 m 110 120 l 110 130 l 120 130 l 120 120 m 120 120 m 200 170 l 200 180 l 210 180 l 210 170 m 210 170 m 170 40 l 170 50 l 180 50 l 180 40 m 180 40 m 100 200 l 100 210 l 110 210 l 110 200 m 110 200 m 230 120 l 230 130 l 240 130 l 240 120 m 240 120 m 220 40 l 220 50 l 230 50 l 230 40 m 230 40 m 190 200 l 190 210 l 200 210 l 200 200 m 200 200 m 280 120 l 280 130 l 290 130 l 290 120 m 290 120 m 190 170 l 190 180 l 200 180 l 200 170 m 200 170 m 170 170 l 170 180 l 180 180 l 180 170 m 180 170 m 240 70 l 240 80 l 250 80 l 250 70 m 250 70 m 200 200 l 200 210 l 210 210 l 210 200 m 210 200 m 220 190 l 220 200 l 230 200 l 230 190 m 230 190 m 40 180 l 40 190 l 50 190 l 50 180 m 50 180 m 60 220 l 60 230 l 70 230 l 70 220 m 70 220 m 250 250 l 250 260 l 260 260 l 260 250 m 260 250 m 250 60 l 250 70 l 260 70 l 260 60 m 260 60 m 70 150 l 70 160 l 80 160 l 80 150 m 80 150 m 270 260 l 270 270 l 280 270 l 280 260 m 280 260 m 80 160 l 80 170 l 90 170 l 90 160 m 90 160 m 60 160 l 60 170 l 70 170 l 70 160 m 70 160 m 130 80 l 130 90 l 140 90 l 140 80 m 140 80 m 140 70 l 140 80 l 150 80 l 150 70 m 150 70 m 100 180 l 100 190 l 110 190 l 110 180 m 110 180 m 180 260 l 180 270 l 190 270 l 190 260 m 190 260 m 150 140 l 150 150 l 160 150 l 160 140 m 160 140 m 40 250 l 40 260 l 50 260 l 50 250 m 50 250 m 200 140 l 200 150 l 210 150 l 210 140 m 210 140 m 180 90 l 180 100 l 190 100 l 190 90 m 190 90 m 170 70 l 170 80 l 180 80 l 180 70 m 180 70 m 160 170 l 160 180 l 170 180 l 170 170 m 170 170 m 280 220 l 280 230 l 290 230 l 290 220 m 290 220 m 220 90 l 220 100 l 230 100 l 230 90 m 230 90 m 50 200 l 50 210 l 60 210 l 60 200 m 60 200 m 280 90 l 280 100 l 290 100 l 290 90 m 290 90 m 240 250 l 240 260 l 250 260 l 250 250 m 250 250 m 170 200 l 170 210 l 180 210 l 180 200 m 180 200 m 240 40 l 240 50 l 250 50 l 250 40 m 250 40 m 40 280 l 40 290 l 50 290 l 50 280 m 50 280 m 220 200 l 220 210 l 230 210 l 230 200 m 230 200 m 40 150 l 40 160 l 50 160 l 50 150 m 50 150 m 270 250 l 270 260 l 280 260 l 280 250 m 280 250 m 70 100 l 70 110 l 80 110 l 80 100 m 80 100 m 60 60 l 60 70 l 70 70 l 70 60 m 70 60 m 120 100 l 120 110 l 130 110 l 130 100 m 130 100 m 270 100 l 270 110 l 280 110 l 280 100 m 280 100 m 260 140 l 260 150 l 270 150 l 270 140 m 270 140 m 140 130 l 140 140 l 150 140 l 150 130 m 150 130 m 100 80 l 100 90 l 110 90 l 110 80 m 110 80 m 150 80 l 150 90 l 160 90 l 160 80 m 160 80 m 200 80 l 200 90 l 210 90 l 210 80 m 210 80 m 140 230 l 140 240 l 150 240 l 150 230 m 150 230 m 40 220 l 40 230 l 50 230 l 50 220 m 50 220 m 190 140 l 190 150 l 200 150 l 200 140 m 200 140 m 180 100 l 180 110 l 190 110 l 190 100 m 190 100 m 200 270 l 200 280 l 210 280 l 210 270 m 210 270 m 240 140 l 240 150 l 250 150 l 250 140 m 250 140 m 220 100 l 220 110 l 230 110 l 230 100 m 230 100 m 40 90 l 40 100 l 50 100 l 50 90 m 50 90 m 280 60 l 280 70 l 290 70 l 290 60 m 290 60 m 190 110 l 190 120 l 200 120 l 200 110 m 200 110 m 250 150 l 250 160 l 260 160 l 260 150 m 260 150 m 170 230 l 170 240 l 180 240 l 180 230 m 180 230 m 60 280 l 60 290 l 70 290 l 70 280 m 70 280 m 50 40 l 50 50 l 60 50 l 60 40 m 60 40 m 40 120 l 40 130 l 50 130 l 50 120 m 50 120 m 260 40 l 260 50 l 270 50 l 270 40 m 270 40 m 130 170 l 130 180 l 140 180 l 140 170 m 140 170 m 90 140 l 90 150 l 100 150 l 100 140 m 100 140 m 80 100 l 80 110 l 90 110 l 90 100 m 90 100 m 70 260 l 70 270 l 80 270 l 80 260 m 80 260 m 120 260 l 120 270 l 130 270 l 130 260 m 130 260 m 100 50 l 100 60 l 110 60 l 110 50 m 110 50 m 150 70 l 150 80 l 160 80 l 160 70 m 160 70 m 130 270 l 130 280 l 140 280 l 140 270 m 140 270 m 180 160 l 180 170 l 190 170 l 190 160 m 190 160 m 100 240 l 100 250 l 110 250 l 110 240 m 110 240 m 160 80 l 160 90 l 170 90 l 170 80 m 170 80 m 150 240 l 150 250 l 160 250 l 160 240 m 160 240 m 210 160 l 210 170 l 220 170 l 220 160 m 220 160 m 190 130 l 190 140 l 200 140 l 200 130 m 200 130 m 180 70 l 180 80 l 190 80 l 190 70 m 190 70 m 170 130 l 170 140 l 180 140 l 180 130 m 180 130 m 280 160 l 280 170 l 290 170 l 290 160 m 290 160 m 200 240 l 200 250 l 210 250 l 210 240 m 210 240 m 160 270 l 160 280 l 170 280 l 170 270 m 170 270 m 40 60 l 40 70 l 50 70 l 50 60 m 50 60 m 250 180 l 250 190 l 260 190 l 260 180 m 260 180 m 170 260 l 170 270 l 180 270 l 180 260 m 180 260 m 70 40 l 70 50 l 80 50 l 80 40 m 80 40 m 60 120 l 60 130 l 70 130 l 70 120 m 70 120 m 120 40 l 120 50 l 130 50 l 130 40 m 130 40 m 70 250 l 70 260 l 80 260 l 80 250 m 80 250 m 140 190 l 140 200 l 150 200 l 150 190 m 150 190 m 100 60 l 100 70 l 110 70 l 110 60 m 110 60 m 80 260 l 80 270 l 90 270 l 90 260 m 90 260 m 130 220 l 130 230 l 140 230 l 140 220 m 140 220 m 190 230 l 190 240 l 200 240 l 200 230 m 200 230 m 280 260 l 280 270 l 290 270 l 290 260 m 290 260 m 240 210 l 240 220 l 250 220 l 250 210 m 250 210 m 220 50 l 220 60 l 230 60 l 230 50 m 230 50 m 280 130 l 280 140 l 290 140 l 290 130 m 290 130 m 190 160 l 190 170 l 200 170 l 200 160 m 200 160 m 200 210 l 200 220 l 210 220 l 210 210 m 210 210 m 160 240 l 160 250 l 170 250 l 170 240 m 170 240 m 250 240 l 250 250 l 260 250 l 260 240 m 260 240 m 220 160 l 220 170 l 230 170 l 230 160 m 230 160 m 190 260 l 190 270 l 200 270 l 200 260 m 200 260 m 70 140 l 70 150 l 80 150 l 80 140 m 80 140 m 50 180 l 50 190 l 60 190 l 60 180 m 60 180 m 260 180 l 260 190 l 270 190 l 270 180 m 270 180 m 80 170 l 80 180 l 90 180 l 90 170 m 90 170 m 90 40 l 90 50 l 100 50 l 100 40 m 100 40 m 80 280 l 80 290 l 90 290 l 90 280 m 90 280 m 70 200 l 70 210 l 80 210 l 80 200 m 80 200 m 140 40 l 140 50 l 150 50 l 150 40 m 150 40 m 130 280 l 130 290 l 140 290 l 140 280 m 140 280 m 120 200 l 120 210 l 130 210 l 130 200 m 130 200 m 180 270 l 180 280 l 190 280 l 190 270 m 190 270 m 40 260 l 40 270 l 50 270 l 50 260 m 50 260 m 200 150 l 200 160 l 210 160 l 210 150 m 210 150 m 110 180 l 110 190 l 120 190 l 120 180 m 120 180 m 170 60 l 170 70 l 180 70 l 180 60 m 180 60 m 160 180 l 160 190 l 170 190 l 170 180 m 170 180 m 230 100 l 230 110 l 240 110 l 240 100 m 240 100 m 220 60 l 220 70 l 230 70 l 230 60 m 230 60 m 210 140 l 210 150 l 220 150 l 220 140 m 220 140 m 190 70 l 190 80 l 200 80 l 200 70 m 200 70 m 280 100 l 280 110 l 290 110 l 290 100 m 290 100 m 260 210 l 260 220 l 270 220 l 270 210 m 270 210 m 100 220 l 100 230 l 110 230 l 110 220 m 110 220 m 60 240 l 60 250 l 70 250 l 70 240 m 70 240 m 240 260 l 240 270 l 250 270 l 250 260 m 250 260 m 260 80 l 260 90 l 270 90 l 270 80 m 270 80 m 250 80 l 250 90 l 260 90 l 260 80 m 260 80 m 70 130 l 70 140 l 80 140 l 80 130 m 80 130 m 60 70 l 60 80 l 70 80 l 70 70 m 70 70 m 50 130 l 50 140 l 60 140 l 60 130 m 60 130 m 80 60 l 80 70 l 90 70 l 90 60 m 90 60 m 100 90 l 100 100 l 110 100 l 110 90 m 110 90 m 150 110 l 150 120 l 160 120 l 160 110 m 160 110 m 200 90 l 200 100 l 210 100 l 210 90 m 210 90 m 100 120 l 100 130 l 110 130 l 110 120 m 110 120 m 180 200 l 180 210 l 190 210 l 190 200 m 190 200 m 160 40 l 160 50 l 170 50 l 170 40 m 170 40 m 150 120 l 150 130 l 160 130 l 160 120 m 160 120 m 230 200 l 230 210 l 240 210 l 240 200 m 240 200 m 40 230 l 40 240 l 50 240 l 50 230 m 50 230 m 110 170 l 110 180 l 120 180 l 120 170 m 120 170 m 180 110 l 180 120 l 190 120 l 190 110 m 190 110 m 170 90 l 170 100 l 180 100 l 180 90 m 180 90 m 190 250 l 190 260 l 200 260 l 200 250 m 200 250 m 240 200 l 240 210 l 250 210 l 250 200 m 250 200 m 50 220 l 50 230 l 60 230 l 60 220 m 60 220 m 40 100 l 40 110 l 50 110 l 50 100 m 50 100 m 280 70 l 280 80 l 290 80 l 290 70 m 290 70 m 210 250 l 210 260 l 220 260 l 220 250 m 220 250 m 250 140 l 250 150 l 260 150 l 260 140 m 260 140 m 240 100 l 240 110 l 250 110 l 250 100 m 250 100 m 220 220 l 220 230 l 230 230 l 230 220 m 230 220 m 40 130 l 40 140 l 50 140 l 50 130 m 50 130 m 70 80 l 70 90 l 80 90 l 80 80 m 80 80 m 60 80 l 60 90 l 70 90 l 70 80 m 70 80 m 130 160 l 130 170 l 140 170 l 140 160 m 140 160 m 140 150 l 140 160 l 150 160 l 150 150 m 150 150 m 130 50 l 130 60 l 140 60 l 140 50 m 140 50 m 100 100 l 100 110 l 110 110 l 110 100 m 110 100 m 90 100 l 90 110 l 100 110 l 100 100 m 100 100 m 80 220 l 80 230 l 90 230 l 90 220 m 90 220 m 150 60 l 150 70 l 160 70 l 160 60 m 160 60 m 140 100 l 140 110 l 150 110 l 150 100 m 150 100 m 100 250 l 100 260 l 110 260 l 110 250 m 110 250 m 160 90 l 160 100 l 170 100 l 170 90 m 170 90 m 150 270 l 150 280 l 160 280 l 160 270 m 160 270 m 40 200 l 40 210 l 50 210 l 50 200 m 50 200 m 190 120 l 190 130 l 200 130 l 200 120 m 200 120 m 180 40 l 180 50 l 190 50 l 190 40 m 190 40 m 280 170 l 280 180 l 290 180 l 290 170 m 290 170 m 100 280 l 100 290 l 110 290 l 110 280 m 110 280 m 230 40 l 230 50 l 240 50 l 240 40 m 240 40 m 40 70 l 40 80 l 50 80 l 50 70 m 50 70 m 280 40 l 280 50 l 290 50 l 290 40 m 290 40 m 210 200 l 210 210 l 220 210 l 220 200 m 220 200 m 200 280 l 200 290 l 210 290 l 210 280 m 210 280 m 70 180 l 70 190 l 80 190 l 80 180 m 80 180 m 250 280 l 250 290 l 260 290 l 260 280 m 260 280 m 220 270 l 220 280 l 230 280 l 230 270 m 230 270 m 260 60 l 260 70 l 270 70 l 270 60 m 270 60 m 80 130 l 80 140 l 90 140 l 90 130 m 90 130 m 70 70 l 70 80 l 80 80 l 80 70 m 80 70 m 80 80 l 80 90 l 90 90 l 90 80 m 90 80 m 70 240 l 70 250 l 80 250 l 80 240 m 80 240 m 100 70 l 100 80 l 110 80 l 110 70 m 110 70 m 150 50 l 150 60 l 160 60 l 160 50 m 160 50 m 130 210 l 130 220 l 140 220 l 140 210 m 140 210 m 110 140 l 110 150 l 120 150 l 120 140 m 120 140 m 200 190 l 200 200 l 210 200 l 210 190 m 210 190 m 100 260 l 100 270 l 110 270 l 110 260 m 110 260 m 240 220 l 240 230 l 250 230 l 250 220 m 250 220 m 230 140 l 230 150 l 240 150 l 240 140 m 240 140 m 150 220 l 150 230 l 160 230 l 160 220 m 160 220 m 140 260 l 140 270 l 150 270 l 150 260 m 150 260 m 280 140 l 280 150 l 290 150 l 290 140 m 290 140 m 200 220 l 200 230 l 210 230 l 210 220 m 210 220 m 260 250 l 260 260 l 270 260 l 270 250 m 270 250 m 160 250 l 160 260 l 170 260 l 170 250 m 170 250 m 60 200 l 60 210 l 70 210 l 70 200 m 70 200 m 220 170 l 220 180 l 230 180 l 230 170 m 230 170 m 40 40 l 40 50 l 50 50 l 50 40 m 50 40 m 270 200 l 270 210 l 280 210 l 280 200 m 280 200 m 50 280 l 50 290 l 60 290 l 60 280 m 60 280 m 250 40 l 250 50 l 260 50 l 260 40 m 260 40 m 170 280 l 170 290 l 180 290 l 180 280 m 180 280 m 50 170 l 50 180 l 60 180 l 60 170 m 60 170 m 120 150 l 120 160 l 130 160 l 130 150 m 130 150 m 220 280 l 220 290 l 230 290 l 230 280 m 230 280 m 80 180 l 80 190 l 90 190 l 90 180 m 90 180 m 60 140 l 60 150 l 70 150 l 70 140 m 70 140 m 130 140 l 130 150 l 140 150 l 140 140 m 140 140 m 120 210 l 120 220 l 130 220 l 130 210 m 130 210 m 100 160 l 100 170 l 110 170 l 110 160 m 110 160 m 80 240 l 80 250 l 90 250 l 90 240 m 90 240 m 150 160 l 150 170 l 160 170 l 160 160 m 160 160 m 230 240 l 230 250 l 240 250 l 240 240 m 240 240 m 40 270 l 40 280 l 50 280 l 50 270 m 50 270 m 280 240 l 280 250 l 290 250 l 290 240 m 290 240 m 180 150 l 180 160 l 190 160 l 190 150 m 190 150 m 170 50 l 170 60 l 180 60 l 180 50 m 180 50 m 160 190 l 160 200 l 170 200 l 170 190 m 170 190 m 230 130 l 230 140 l 240 140 l 240 130 m 240 130 m 220 70 l 220 80 l 230 80 l 230 70 m 230 70 m 210 130 l 210 140 l 220 140 l 220 130 m 220 130 m 100 230 l 100 240 l 110 240 l 110 230 m 110 230 m 240 270 l 240 280 l 250 280 l 250 270 m 250 270 m 240 60 l 240 70 l 250 70 l 250 60 m 250 60 m 60 250 l 60 260 l 70 260 l 70 250 m 70 250 m 250 70 l 250 80 l 260 80 l 260 70 m 260 70 m 190 270 l 190 280 l 200 280 l 200 270 m 200 270 m 60 40 l 60 50 l 70 50 l 70 40 m 70 40 m 270 40 l 270 50 l 280 50 l 280 40 m 280 40 m 260 120 l 260 130 l 270 130 l 270 120 m 270 120 m 80 70 l 80 80 l 90 80 l 90 70 m 90 70 m 60 190 l 60 200 l 70 200 l 70 190 m 70 190 m 270 170 l 270 180 l 280 180 l 280 170 m 280 170

29
00:00:21,940 --> 00:00:24,820
The war is over. Winter has come.

30
00:00:24,820 --> 00:00:26,250
The war is not over.

31
00:00:26,250 --> 00:00:28,760
The true enemy won't wait out the storm.

32
00:00:30,320 --> 00:00:37,410
The King in the North! The King in the North!

33
00:00:38,500 --> 00:00:41,900
Our uncle Euron returned home after a long absence.

34
00:00:43,770 --> 00:00:45,130
He murdered our father,

35
00:00:45,130 --> 00:00:47,100
and took the Salt Throne from Yara.

36
00:00:47,160 --> 00:00:49,060
He would have murdered us if we'd stayed.

37
00:00:49,110 --> 00:00:53,260
Build me a thousand ships, and I will give you this world.

38
00:00:55,290 --> 00:00:56,640
There's a storm coming.

39
00:00:56,640 --> 00:00:58,240
You'll be wanting a roof tonight.

40
00:00:58,810 --> 00:01:00,010
I don't have much,

41
00:01:00,020 --> 00:01:02,600
but I have hidden a bit of silver from the bandits.

42
00:01:04,090 --> 00:01:05,220
What did you do?!

43
00:01:05,300 --> 00:01:07,020
They'll both be dead come winter.

44
00:01:07,830 --> 00:01:09,680
Cold winds are rising in the North.

45
00:01:09,680 --> 00:01:11,360
We need good men to help us.

46
00:01:11,360 --> 00:01:14,480
You can still help a lot more than you've harmed, Clegane.

47
00:01:14,490 --> 00:01:15,940
It's not too late for you.

48
00:01:17,170 --> 00:01:19,010
Send me to Oldtown.

49
00:01:19,010 --> 00:01:20,740
I'm to be the new maester.

50
00:01:21,910 --> 00:01:24,280
The Citadel has the world's greatest library.

51
00:01:24,280 --> 00:01:26,920
I'll learn about things that all help when...

52
00:01:28,220 --> 00:01:29,140
when they come.

53
00:01:32,890 --> 00:01:34,060
Hodor, hurry!

54
00:01:42,830 --> 00:01:45,150
Are you sure you're ready for this?

55
00:01:45,350 --> 00:01:49,530
I'm the three-eyed raven now. I have to be ready for this.

56
00:01:51,410 --> 00:01:54,440
Do you know who had this table carved and painted, Ser Davos?

57
00:01:54,440 --> 00:01:55,720
Aegon Targaryen.

58
00:01:55,830 --> 00:01:57,190
Aegon used to live here,

59
00:01:57,190 --> 00:01:59,100
and the Targaryens built this castle.

60
00:01:59,100 --> 00:01:59,970
Aye. So they did.

61
00:01:59,970 --> 00:02:03,830
I want us both to go home. But they took it from us.

62
00:02:03,830 --> 00:02:05,580
How do we go home?

63
00:02:06,260 --> 00:02:07,970
You're in the great game now,

64
00:02:08,150 --> 00:02:11,680
and the great game's terrifying. Are you afraid?

65
00:02:13,720 --> 00:02:17,310
My name is Arya Stark. I want you to know that.

66
00:02:57,600 --> 00:03:01,440
You're wondering why I brought you all here.

67
00:03:01,660 --> 00:03:05,060
After all, we just had a feast.

68
00:03:05,360 --> 00:03:07,780
Since when does old Walder

69
00:03:07,780 --> 00:03:11,270
give us two feasts in a single fortnight?

70
00:03:13,450 --> 00:03:16,340
Well, it's no good being Lord of the Riverlands

71
00:03:16,340 --> 00:03:18,710
if you can't celebrate with your family.

72
00:03:18,710 --> 00:03:20,340
That's what I say!

73
00:03:20,360 --> 00:03:24,020
Yes!

74
00:03:27,640 --> 00:03:31,720
I've gathered every Frey who means a damn thing

75
00:03:32,000 --> 00:03:35,970
so I can tell you my plans for this great house

76
00:03:36,160 --> 00:03:38,670
now that winter has come.

77
00:03:39,680 --> 00:03:43,080
But first, a toast!

78
00:03:44,350 --> 00:03:47,510
No more of that Dornish horse piss!

79
00:03:47,960 --> 00:03:50,800
This is the finest Arbor gold!

80
00:03:50,980 --> 00:03:54,170
Proper wine for proper heroes!

81
00:03:59,230 --> 00:04:01,300
Stand together!

82
00:04:01,360 --> 00:04:03,210
Stand together!

83
00:04:12,560 --> 00:04:13,560
Not you.

84
00:04:13,870 --> 00:04:16,970
I'm not wasting good wine on a damn woman.

85
00:04:20,340 --> 00:04:24,350
Maybe I'm not the most pleasant man.

86
00:04:24,730 --> 00:04:28,220
I'll admit it. But I'm proud of you lot.

87
00:04:28,230 --> 00:04:31,230
You're my family, the men who helped me

88
00:04:31,230 --> 00:04:34,440
slaughter the Starks at the Red Wedding.

89
00:04:35,490 --> 00:04:38,700
Yes, yes.

90
00:04:39,080 --> 00:04:40,240
Cheer.

91
00:04:41,260 --> 00:04:44,170
Brave men, all of you.

92
00:04:44,680 --> 00:04:48,090
Butchered a woman pregnant with her babe.

93
00:04:49,010 --> 00:04:52,400
Cut the throat of a mother of five.

94
00:04:54,070 --> 00:04:58,870
Slaughtered your guests after inviting them into your home.

95
00:05:00,530 --> 00:05:06,290
But you didn't slaughter every one of the Starks.

96
00:05:07,120 --> 00:05:10,540
No, no, that was your mistake.

97
00:05:10,900 --> 00:05:14,850
You should have ripped them all out, root and stem.

98
00:05:21,350 --> 00:05:23,550
Leave one wolf alive

99
00:05:23,550 --> 00:05:26,050
and the sheep are never safe.

100
00:05:52,100 --> 00:05:54,040
When people ask you what happened here...

101
00:05:55,480 --> 00:05:57,430
tell them the North remembers.

102
00:05:58,860 --> 00:06:02,600
Tell them winter came for House Frey.

104
00:10:25,120 --> 00:10:26,610
You wildlings?

105
00:10:26,870 --> 00:10:30,020
I'm Meera Reed, daughter of Howland Reed.

106
00:10:31,700 --> 00:10:33,350
This is Brandon Stark,

107
00:10:33,840 --> 00:10:35,420
son of Ned Stark.

108
00:10:39,750 --> 00:10:41,400
How do I know that's true?

109
00:10:44,800 --> 00:10:46,780
You were at the Fist of the First Men.

110
00:10:48,220 --> 00:10:49,590
You were at Hardhome.

111
00:10:51,590 --> 00:10:53,590
You've seen the Army of the Dead.

112
00:10:55,180 --> 00:10:56,670
You've seen the Night King.

113
00:10:57,470 --> 00:10:58,840
He's coming for us.

114
00:11:00,580 --> 00:11:01,800
For all of us.

115
00:11:09,850 --> 00:11:10,810
Okay, come on.

116
00:11:11,940 --> 00:11:13,280
Let's get them inside.

117
00:11:42,860 --> 00:11:46,050
I want every northern maester to scour their records

118
00:11:46,060 --> 00:11:48,490
for any mention of dragonglass.

119
00:11:49,360 --> 00:11:51,240
Dragonglass kills white walkers.

120
00:11:51,240 --> 00:11:53,610
It's more valuable to us now than gold.

121
00:11:53,900 --> 00:11:55,530
We need to find it, we need to mine it,

122
00:11:55,540 --> 00:11:57,440
we need to make weapons from it.

123
00:11:58,700 --> 00:12:01,450
Everyone aged 10 to 60

124
00:12:01,720 --> 00:12:05,050
will drill daily with spears, pikes, bow and arrow.

125
00:12:05,050 --> 00:12:08,370
It's about time we taught these boys of summer how to fight.

126
00:12:09,140 --> 00:12:10,490
Not just the boys.

127
00:12:11,120 --> 00:12:12,810
We can't defend the North

128
00:12:12,940 --> 00:12:15,300
if only half the population is fighting.

129
00:12:15,960 --> 00:12:20,210
You expect me to put a spear in my granddaughter's hand?

130
00:12:20,480 --> 00:12:23,700
I don't plan on knitting by the fire while men fight for me.

131
00:12:23,700 --> 00:12:26,670
I might be small, Lord Glover, and I might be a girl,

132
00:12:26,670 --> 00:12:29,320
but I am every bit as much a Northerner as you.

133
00:12:29,320 --> 00:12:30,680
Indeed you are, my lady. No one has questioned--

134
00:12:30,680 --> 00:12:33,210
And I don't need your permission to defend the North.

135
00:12:36,150 --> 00:12:37,460
We'll begin training every man,

136
00:12:37,460 --> 00:12:40,650
woman, boy, and girl on Bear Island.

137
00:12:40,920 --> 00:12:42,000
Aye!

138
00:12:42,950 --> 00:12:44,220
While we're preparing for attack,

139
00:12:44,230 --> 00:12:45,910
we need to shore up our defenses.

140
00:12:46,890 --> 00:12:47,820
The only thing standing

141
00:12:47,820 --> 00:12:50,200
between us and the Army of the Dead is the Wall,

142
00:12:50,200 --> 00:12:53,430
and the Wall hasn't been properly manned in centuries.

143
00:12:54,210 --> 00:12:56,500
I'm not the king of the Free Folk.

144
00:12:58,310 --> 00:13:00,610
But if we're going to survive this winter together...

145
00:13:02,010 --> 00:13:04,640
You want us to man the castles for you?

146
00:13:05,120 --> 00:13:05,920
Aye.

147
00:13:06,360 --> 00:13:08,910
Last time we saw the Night King was at Hardhome.

148
00:13:09,140 --> 00:13:12,260
The closest castle to Hardhome is Eastwatch-by-the-Sea.

149
00:13:12,260 --> 00:13:14,090
Then that's where I'll go.

150
00:13:14,340 --> 00:13:16,930
Looks like we're the Night's Watch now.

151
00:13:19,110 --> 00:13:20,820
If they breach the Wall,

152
00:13:20,820 --> 00:13:22,510
the first two castles in their path

153
00:13:22,510 --> 00:13:24,880
are Last Hearth and Karhold.

154
00:13:25,020 --> 00:13:28,280
The Umbers and the Karstarks betrayed the North.

155
00:13:28,680 --> 00:13:30,310
Their castles should be torn down

156
00:13:30,310 --> 00:13:32,120
with not a stone left standing.

157
00:13:32,120 --> 00:13:34,640
The castles committed no crimes.

158
00:13:34,820 --> 00:13:38,150
And we need every fortress we have for the war to come.

159
00:13:38,150 --> 00:13:41,380
We should give the Last Hearth and Karhold to new families,

160
00:13:41,380 --> 00:13:44,270
loyal families who supported us against Ramsay.

161
00:13:44,290 --> 00:13:46,060
Aye!

162
00:13:47,960 --> 00:13:49,620
The Umbers and the Karstarks

163
00:13:49,620 --> 00:13:51,990
have fought beside the Starks for centuries.

164
00:13:51,990 --> 00:13:54,550
They've kept faith for generation after generation.

165
00:13:54,550 --> 00:13:56,120
And then they broke faith.

166
00:13:56,120 --> 00:13:59,100
I'm not going to strip these families of their ancestral homes

167
00:13:59,100 --> 00:14:01,590
because of the crimes of a few reckless sons.

168
00:14:01,590 --> 00:14:03,330
So there's no punishment for treason

169
00:14:03,330 --> 00:14:05,340
and no reward for loyalty?

170
00:14:11,090 --> 00:14:13,220
The punishment for treason is death.

171
00:14:14,050 --> 00:14:16,620
Smalljon Umber died on the field of battle.

172
00:14:16,620 --> 00:14:19,410
Harald Karstark died on the field of battle.

173
00:14:19,410 --> 00:14:21,780
They died fighting for Ramsay.

174
00:14:21,860 --> 00:14:23,380
Give the castles to the families

175
00:14:23,380 --> 00:14:25,980
of the men who died fighting for you.

176
00:14:39,050 --> 00:14:41,930
When I was Lord Commander of the Night's Watch...

177
00:14:43,450 --> 00:14:45,710
I executed men who betrayed me.

178
00:14:46,220 --> 00:14:49,540
I executed men who refused to follow orders.

179
00:14:49,890 --> 00:14:51,620
My father always said,

180
00:14:51,880 --> 00:14:54,360
"The man who passes the sentence should swing the sword,"

181
00:14:54,360 --> 00:14:57,090
and I have tried to live by those words.

182
00:14:57,770 --> 00:15:01,020
But I will not punish a son for his father's sins,

183
00:15:01,120 --> 00:15:03,270
and I will not take a family home

184
00:15:03,270 --> 00:15:06,600
away from a family it has belonged to for centuries.

185
00:15:07,020 --> 00:15:08,880
That is my decision,

186
00:15:09,510 --> 00:15:11,780
and my decision is final.

187
00:15:18,300 --> 00:15:19,400
Ned Umber.

188
00:15:27,310 --> 00:15:28,930
Alys Karstark.

189
00:15:43,810 --> 00:15:45,560
For centuries, our families fought

190
00:15:45,560 --> 00:15:47,610
side by side on the battlefield.

191
00:15:48,450 --> 00:15:52,880
I ask you to pledge your loyalty once again to House Stark,

192
00:15:53,440 --> 00:15:55,510
to serve as our bannermen

193
00:15:55,970 --> 00:15:59,020
and come to our aid whenever called upon.

194
00:16:07,540 --> 00:16:08,470
Stand.

195
00:16:12,270 --> 00:16:14,630
Yesterday's wars don't matter anymore.

196
00:16:15,260 --> 00:16:17,700
The North needs to band together,

197
00:16:17,930 --> 00:16:20,030
all the living north.

198
00:16:20,870 --> 00:16:23,530
Will you stand beside me, Ned and Alys,

199
00:16:23,540 --> 00:16:25,380
now and always?

200
00:16:25,380 --> 00:16:27,650
Now and always!

201
00:16:47,080 --> 00:16:49,300
You are my sister, but I am king now.

202
00:16:49,390 --> 00:16:50,850
Will you start wearing a crown?

203
00:16:50,850 --> 00:16:52,200
When you question my decisions

204
00:16:52,200 --> 00:16:54,670
in front of the other lords and ladies, you undermine me.

205
00:16:54,670 --> 00:16:56,540
So I can't question your decisions anymore?

206
00:16:56,540 --> 00:16:57,460
Of course you can, but--

207
00:16:57,460 --> 00:16:59,550
Joffrey never let anyone question his authority.

208
00:16:59,550 --> 00:17:01,200
You think he was a good king?

209
00:17:03,650 --> 00:17:05,180
Do you think I'm Joffrey?

210
00:17:09,140 --> 00:17:11,800
You're as far from Joffrey as anyone I've ever met.

211
00:17:12,090 --> 00:17:13,030
Thank you.

212
00:17:15,550 --> 00:17:16,880
You're good at this, you know.

213
00:17:16,880 --> 00:17:18,920
- At what? - At ruling.

214
00:17:20,590 --> 00:17:21,300
No.

215
00:17:21,320 --> 00:17:22,230
You are.

216
00:17:23,100 --> 00:17:24,030
You are.

217
00:17:26,730 --> 00:17:28,540
They respect you, they really do,

218
00:17:28,540 --> 00:17:29,710
but you have to

219
00:17:30,790 --> 00:17:32,070
Why are you laughing?

220
00:17:33,100 --> 00:17:34,340
What did father used to say?

221
00:17:34,340 --> 00:17:37,410
Everything before the word "But" is horse shit.

222
00:17:37,810 --> 00:17:39,110
He never said that to me.

223
00:17:39,120 --> 00:17:42,010
No. No, he never cursed in front of his girls.

224
00:17:42,010 --> 00:17:44,100
Because he was trying to protect us.

225
00:17:45,110 --> 00:17:47,960
He never wanted us to see how dirty the world really is,

226
00:17:47,960 --> 00:17:50,890
but Father couldn't protect me and neither can you.

227
00:17:50,940 --> 00:17:53,360
- Stop trying. - All right, I'll stop trying to protect you

228
00:17:53,360 --> 00:17:54,750
and you stop trying to undermine me.

229
00:17:54,750 --> 00:17:56,610
I'm not trying to undermine you!

230
00:17:58,610 --> 00:18:01,120
You have to be smarter than Father.

231
00:18:01,760 --> 00:18:03,540
You need to be smarter than Robb.

232
00:18:04,380 --> 00:18:05,910
I loved them, I miss them,

233
00:18:05,920 --> 00:18:07,220
but they made stupid mistakes,

234
00:18:07,220 --> 00:18:09,340
and they both lost their heads for it.

235
00:18:09,340 --> 00:18:11,100
And how should I be smarter?

236
00:18:11,570 --> 00:18:12,960
By listening to you?

237
00:18:15,140 --> 00:18:16,580
Would that be so terrible?

238
00:18:18,210 --> 00:18:21,370
A raven from King's Landing, Your Grace.

239
00:18:31,110 --> 00:18:33,390
"Cersei of House Lannister, First of Her Name,

240
00:18:33,390 --> 00:18:35,440
Queen of the Andals and the First Men,

241
00:18:35,440 --> 00:18:36,920
Protector of the Seven Kingdoms--"

242
00:18:36,920 --> 00:18:38,160
What does she want?

243
00:18:40,530 --> 00:18:42,000
Come to King's Landing.

244
00:18:42,510 --> 00:18:45,610
Bend the knee or suffer the fate of all traitors.

245
00:18:46,470 --> 00:18:48,420
You've been so consumed with the enemy to the north,

246
00:18:48,420 --> 00:18:50,400
you've forgotten about the one to the south.

247
00:18:50,400 --> 00:18:52,880
I'm consumed with the Night King because I've seen him.

248
00:18:53,320 --> 00:18:55,580
And believe me, you'd think of little else if you had, too.

249
00:18:55,580 --> 00:18:57,510
We still have a wall between us and the Night King.

250
00:18:57,510 --> 00:18:59,440
There's nothing between us and Cersei.

251
00:18:59,440 --> 00:19:02,130
There's a thousand miles between us and Cersei.

252
00:19:02,370 --> 00:19:05,030
Winter is here. The Lannisters are a southern army.

253
00:19:05,110 --> 00:19:06,890
They've never ranged this far north.

254
00:19:06,890 --> 00:19:09,380
You're the military man, but I know her.

255
00:19:10,080 --> 00:19:13,330
If you're her enemy, she'll never stop until she's destroyed you.

256
00:19:13,330 --> 00:19:16,660
Everyone who's ever crossed her, she's found a way to murder.

257
00:19:19,570 --> 00:19:21,650
You almost sound as if you admire her.

258
00:19:25,390 --> 00:19:27,250
I learned a great deal from her.

259
00:20:04,010 --> 00:20:05,330
What is this?

260
00:20:06,200 --> 00:20:08,440
It's what we've been waiting for our whole lives.

261
00:20:08,660 --> 00:20:11,240
It's what Father trained us for, whether he knew it or not.

262
00:20:11,240 --> 00:20:12,290
He knew it.

263
00:20:12,930 --> 00:20:14,740
Made me memorize every damn city, town,

264
00:20:14,740 --> 00:20:16,360
lake, forest, and mountain.

265
00:20:16,360 --> 00:20:18,740
It's ours now. We just have to take it.

266
00:20:20,250 --> 00:20:22,190
You've been quiet since you came home.

267
00:20:22,770 --> 00:20:23,780
Are you angry with me?

268
00:20:23,780 --> 00:20:25,770
No, not angry.

269
00:20:27,220 --> 00:20:28,460
Are you afraid of me?

270
00:20:30,420 --> 00:20:31,550
Should I be?

271
00:20:35,520 --> 00:20:38,670
Daenerys Targaryen has chosen Tyrion to be her Hand.

272
00:20:39,320 --> 00:20:41,810
Right now, they're sailing across the Narrow Sea,

273
00:20:42,020 --> 00:20:44,470
hoping to take back her father's throne.

274
00:20:44,980 --> 00:20:46,170
Our little brother,

275
00:20:47,390 --> 00:20:49,490
the one you love so much,

276
00:20:49,610 --> 00:20:50,800
the one you set free,

277
00:20:51,460 --> 00:20:54,270
the one who murdered our father and our first-born son,

278
00:20:54,690 --> 00:20:57,930
now he stands beside our enemies and gives them counsel.

279
00:21:01,740 --> 00:21:04,290
He's out there somewhere at the head of an armada.

280
00:21:05,890 --> 00:21:07,280
Where will they land?

281
00:21:10,080 --> 00:21:11,510
Dragonstone.

282
00:21:12,100 --> 00:21:14,310
They have deep-water ports for the ships.

283
00:21:14,310 --> 00:21:16,260
Stannis left the castle unoccupied,

284
00:21:16,270 --> 00:21:17,830
and that's where she was born.

285
00:21:18,510 --> 00:21:20,020
Enemies to the east.

286
00:21:20,410 --> 00:21:21,770
Enemies to the south--

287
00:21:21,770 --> 00:21:24,580
Ellaria Sand and her brood of bitches.

289
00:21:24,580 --> 00:21:26,110
Enemies to the west--

290
00:21:26,610 --> 00:21:28,470
Olenna, the old cunt.

291
00:21:28,470 --> 00:21:29,650
Another traitor.

293
00:21:31,980 --> 00:21:33,580
Enemies to the north.

294
00:21:34,030 --> 00:21:36,490
Ned Stark's bastard has been named King in the North

295
00:21:36,490 --> 00:21:39,890
and that murdering whore Sansa stands beside him.

296
00:21:40,200 --> 00:21:42,720
Enemies everywhere. We're surrounded by traitors.

297
00:21:42,730 --> 00:21:44,220
You're in command of the Lannister army now.

298
00:21:44,220 --> 00:21:46,640
- How do we proceed? - Winter is here.

299
00:21:47,680 --> 00:21:51,330
We can't win a war if we can't feed our men and our horses.

300
00:21:51,550 --> 00:21:54,800
The Tyrells have the grain, the Tyrells have the livestock.

301
00:21:55,080 --> 00:21:57,020
Will the Tyrell bannermen stand alongside

302
00:21:57,020 --> 00:22:00,290
a Dothraki horde and Unsullied slave soldiers?

303
00:22:00,290 --> 00:22:02,600
If they think Daenerys will win.

304
00:22:02,940 --> 00:22:05,110
No one wants to fight on the losing side.

305
00:22:05,110 --> 00:22:08,460
Right now, we look like the losing side.

306
00:22:09,550 --> 00:22:10,870
I'm the Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.

307
00:22:10,870 --> 00:22:13,200
Three kingdoms, at best.

308
00:22:14,300 --> 00:22:16,410
I'm not sure you understand how much danger we're in.

309
00:22:16,410 --> 00:22:18,100
I understand we're in a war for survival.

310
00:22:18,100 --> 00:22:20,240
I understand whoever loses dies.

311
00:22:21,460 --> 00:22:23,050
I understand whoever wins could launch a dynasty

312
00:22:23,050 --> 00:22:24,770
that lasts a thousand years.

313
00:22:24,770 --> 00:22:26,500
A dynasty for whom?

314
00:22:27,830 --> 00:22:29,920
Our children are dead.

315
00:22:30,930 --> 00:22:32,530
We're the last of us.

316
00:22:32,930 --> 00:22:34,370
A dynasty for us, then.

317
00:22:37,310 --> 00:22:39,240
We never talked about Tommen.

318
00:22:42,160 --> 00:22:43,590
There's nothing to say.

319
00:22:43,860 --> 00:22:45,920
Our baby boy killed himself.

320
00:22:45,920 --> 00:22:47,100
He betrayed me.

321
00:22:47,380 --> 00:22:48,960
He betrayed us both.

322
00:22:49,100 --> 00:22:50,700
Should we spend our days mourning the dead--

323
00:22:50,700 --> 00:22:52,430
mother, father, and all our children?

324
00:22:52,430 --> 00:22:54,550
- Cersei-- - I loved them. I did.

325
00:22:55,190 --> 00:22:57,700
But they're ashes now and we're still flesh and blood.

326
00:22:58,190 --> 00:23:00,930
We're the last Lannisters, the last ones who count.

327
00:23:06,890 --> 00:23:09,390
Even Lannisters can't survive without allies.

328
00:23:09,390 --> 00:23:11,470
Where are our allies now?

329
00:23:12,820 --> 00:23:15,030
You saw what happened to Walder Frey and his family.

330
00:23:15,030 --> 00:23:16,140
I heard.

331
00:23:16,530 --> 00:23:19,050
- How could we ever trust a man like that? - We couldn't.

332
00:23:19,050 --> 00:23:20,860
He was a useless, old coward,

333
00:23:20,860 --> 00:23:23,070
but the Freys supported us.

334
00:23:23,430 --> 00:23:24,150
Now they're all dead.

335
00:23:24,150 --> 00:23:25,790
Whoever killed them is no friend of ours.

336
00:23:25,800 --> 00:23:27,490
We need allies.

337
00:23:27,510 --> 00:23:29,210
Stronger, better allies.

338
00:23:29,220 --> 00:23:30,990
We can't win this war alone.

339
00:23:33,690 --> 00:23:35,920
You think I listened to Father for 40 years

340
00:23:35,920 --> 00:23:36,900
and learned nothing?

341
00:24:14,120 --> 00:24:15,600
The Greyjoys?

342
00:24:15,700 --> 00:24:18,170
You invited the Greyjoys to King's Landing?

343
00:24:18,170 --> 00:24:20,550
- Not all of them. - Well, it looks like all of them.

344
00:24:20,970 --> 00:24:22,210
I invited Euron Greyjoy,

345
00:24:22,210 --> 00:24:24,470
the new King of the Iron Islands.

346
00:24:25,120 --> 00:24:28,040
You said yourself we needed stronger, better allies.

347
00:24:28,290 --> 00:24:30,780
- There you are. - How are they better allies?

348
00:24:30,780 --> 00:24:33,100
How are they different from the Freys?

349
00:24:33,320 --> 00:24:34,410
They both broke their promises

350
00:24:34,410 --> 00:24:37,270
and murdered their former friends as soon as it suited them.

351
00:24:37,270 --> 00:24:39,990
So does everyone when it suits them.

352
00:24:40,200 --> 00:24:42,730
Unlike the Freys, they have ships.

353
00:24:42,890 --> 00:24:45,610
- And they're good at killing. - They're not good at anything.

354
00:24:45,610 --> 00:24:48,980
I know the ironborn. They're bitter, angry little people.

355
00:24:49,050 --> 00:24:49,750
All they know how to do is

356
00:24:49,750 --> 00:24:52,340
steal things they can't build or grow themselves.

357
00:24:52,340 --> 00:24:54,140
Euron Greyjoy didn't come here for that.

358
00:24:54,150 --> 00:24:56,090
Oh, what did he come here for, then?

359
00:24:56,610 --> 00:24:57,870
A queen.

360
00:25:10,960 --> 00:25:13,540
The moment I was chosen Lord of the Iron Islands,

361
00:25:13,930 --> 00:25:15,180
they turned on me.

362
00:25:16,160 --> 00:25:17,340
Their own uncle.

363
00:25:17,530 --> 00:25:19,510
They stole my best ships and ran.

364
00:25:20,560 --> 00:25:22,200
Sailed them right across the world

365
00:25:22,200 --> 00:25:24,200
and gave them to the Dragon Queen

366
00:25:24,200 --> 00:25:27,530
so she could bring her armies here to attack you.

367
00:25:28,890 --> 00:25:31,480
It's nothing compared to the treason you suffered

368
00:25:31,480 --> 00:25:35,080
at the hands of a family member, from what I hear.

369
00:25:35,080 --> 00:25:37,700
But still, it bothers me.

370
00:25:39,610 --> 00:25:42,130
Murdering them would make me feel a lot better.

371
00:25:42,770 --> 00:25:46,490
And since it appears that all our treasonous family members

372
00:25:46,490 --> 00:25:48,600
are fighting for the same side,

373
00:25:48,940 --> 00:25:50,970
I thought we rightful monarchs

374
00:25:51,690 --> 00:25:53,280
could murder them together.

375
00:25:59,990 --> 00:26:02,850
You're not a rightful monarch, though, are you?

376
00:26:06,780 --> 00:26:08,050
The Greyjoys rebelled against

377
00:26:08,050 --> 00:26:09,590
the throne for the right to be monarchs,

378
00:26:09,590 --> 00:26:13,240
but as I recall, you were soundly defeated.

379
00:26:13,710 --> 00:26:14,890
Come to mention it,

380
00:26:15,560 --> 00:26:17,990
weren't you the one who started that rebellion

381
00:26:17,990 --> 00:26:21,630
by sailing to Casterly Rock and burning the Lannister fleet?

382
00:26:22,270 --> 00:26:24,050
You certainly caught us there.

383
00:26:24,280 --> 00:26:26,600
Very smart move on your part.

384
00:26:26,850 --> 00:26:30,050
Of course, we all made it to the Iron Islands anyway.

385
00:26:30,970 --> 00:26:32,040
I was there.

386
00:26:32,100 --> 00:26:33,610
I remember very well.

387
00:26:33,940 --> 00:26:34,960
I saw you.

388
00:26:35,390 --> 00:26:37,150
I heard so much talk.

389
00:26:37,910 --> 00:26:40,460
The best in the world. No one can stop him.

390
00:26:41,190 --> 00:26:43,060
I didn't believe it, to be honest.

391
00:26:43,610 --> 00:26:46,230
But I must say when you rushed through the breach

392
00:26:46,230 --> 00:26:48,370
and started cutting people down...

393
00:26:52,000 --> 00:26:53,900
it was glorious.

394
00:26:54,000 --> 00:26:55,400
Like a dance.

395
00:26:55,400 --> 00:26:58,430
The people I was cutting down were your own kin.

396
00:26:58,430 --> 00:26:59,970
The place was getting crowded.

397
00:27:00,940 --> 00:27:03,210
I enjoyed watching it. I truly did.

398
00:27:03,210 --> 00:27:05,460
And I enjoyed killing Greyjoys.

399
00:27:05,470 --> 00:27:06,860
A good thing for me.

400
00:27:08,210 --> 00:27:11,450
If you hadn't crushed us, I wouldn't have gone into exile.

401
00:27:11,510 --> 00:27:12,880
If I hadn't done that,

402
00:27:13,530 --> 00:27:16,840
I wouldn't be the greatest captain on the 14 seas.

403
00:27:18,100 --> 00:27:19,580
If not the most humble.

404
00:27:21,250 --> 00:27:22,430
You're not humble.

405
00:27:24,320 --> 00:27:26,690
You're the queen of a great nation.

406
00:27:27,490 --> 00:27:29,510
You don't care about the Iron Islands.

407
00:27:29,510 --> 00:27:33,720
They're nothing but rocks and bird shit and--

408
00:27:33,920 --> 00:27:36,440
and a lot of very unattractive people.

409
00:27:37,030 --> 00:27:39,520
The Iron Fleet, on the other hand,

410
00:27:39,730 --> 00:27:41,700
that's something else entirely.

411
00:27:42,690 --> 00:27:45,680
It's the greatest armada Westeros has ever seen.

412
00:27:46,390 --> 00:27:49,290
With the Iron Fleet, you own the seas.

413
00:27:50,620 --> 00:27:52,920
You can defeat the invaders of the east

414
00:27:53,130 --> 00:27:55,540
and the pretenders of the north and south.

415
00:27:56,400 --> 00:27:57,910
What do you want in return?

416
00:27:59,810 --> 00:28:01,710
Ever since I was a little boy,

417
00:28:03,070 --> 00:28:04,590
I wanted to grow up and marry

418
00:28:04,590 --> 00:28:06,990
the most beautiful woman in the world.

419
00:28:07,670 --> 00:28:09,150
So here I am,

420
00:28:09,500 --> 00:28:11,260
with a thousand ships

421
00:28:12,080 --> 00:28:13,660
and two good hands.

422
00:28:19,080 --> 00:28:20,830
I decline your proposal.

423
00:28:23,410 --> 00:28:24,730
Why?

424
00:28:24,740 --> 00:28:26,420
You're not trustworthy.

425
00:28:27,220 --> 00:28:29,170
You've broken promises to allies before

426
00:28:29,180 --> 00:28:31,670
and murdered them at the nearest opportunity.

427
00:28:31,930 --> 00:28:33,350
You murdered your own brother.

428
00:28:34,550 --> 00:28:37,030
You should try it. Feels wonderful.

429
00:28:38,620 --> 00:28:40,640
I don't expect you to trust me outright.

430
00:28:40,640 --> 00:28:43,200
You need proof of my honest intentions.

431
00:28:43,210 --> 00:28:44,560
In my experience,

432
00:28:44,660 --> 00:28:47,420
the surest way to a woman's heart is with a gift.

433
00:28:47,750 --> 00:28:49,000
A priceless gift.

434
00:28:49,780 --> 00:28:51,670
I won't return to King's Landing

435
00:28:51,900 --> 00:28:53,440
until I have that for you.

436
00:31:59,610 --> 00:32:01,590
Ah, Maester Weyland.

437
00:32:02,940 --> 00:32:06,160
A drinker's liver if ever I saw one.

438
00:32:07,400 --> 00:32:08,390
Weigh that.

439
00:32:09,350 --> 00:32:12,040
The triumph of transitory pleasures.

440
00:32:12,810 --> 00:32:14,620
Mankind's curse.

441
00:32:14,620 --> 00:32:17,650
Archmaester, I was wondering...

442
00:32:17,980 --> 00:32:19,060
What's the weight?

443
00:32:19,530 --> 00:32:23,520
147
Um, 147.

444
00:32:25,820 --> 00:32:28,810
I was wondering if you had considered my proposition.

445
00:32:29,090 --> 00:32:30,950
I don't remember your proposition.

446
00:32:31,900 --> 00:32:34,880
I asked you if, in light of what I've seen in the North,

447
00:32:35,060 --> 00:32:38,160
if I could have access to the restricted area of the library.

448
00:32:38,210 --> 00:32:39,650
That area is reserved for maesters.

449
00:32:39,660 --> 00:32:41,660
- Are you a maester? - No.

450
00:32:42,620 --> 00:32:44,620
Not a very strong proposition, is it?

451
00:32:53,730 --> 00:32:56,360
Archmaester, with respect,

452
00:32:56,940 --> 00:32:58,110
I've seen them...

453
00:32:58,390 --> 00:32:59,740
the Army of the Dead.

454
00:33:00,590 --> 00:33:01,920
The white walkers.

455
00:33:03,770 --> 00:33:06,010
I was sent here to learn how to defeat them,

456
00:33:06,090 --> 00:33:07,780
but everyone in the Citadel,

457
00:33:08,110 --> 00:33:09,770
those who will even talk to me,

458
00:33:10,400 --> 00:33:13,270
they all doubt the walkers ever existed in the first place.

459
00:33:13,610 --> 00:33:15,560
Everyone in the Citadel doubts everything.

460
00:33:15,560 --> 00:33:16,620
It's their job.

461
00:33:22,630 --> 00:33:25,520
But the tales of the Long Night can't be pure fabrication.

462
00:33:27,380 --> 00:33:30,080
Too many similarities from unconnected sources.

463
00:33:30,630 --> 00:33:32,720
Sources in the restricted area?

464
00:33:32,720 --> 00:33:33,930
The very same.

465
00:33:35,670 --> 00:33:37,190
And the simplest explanation

466
00:33:37,190 --> 00:33:39,970
for your grating obsession with the white walkers

467
00:33:39,970 --> 00:33:41,730
is that you're telling the truth

468
00:33:41,920 --> 00:33:43,470
and that you saw what you say you saw.

469
00:33:44,820 --> 00:33:47,710
So, you believe me.

470
00:33:48,610 --> 00:33:49,660
I do.

471
00:33:50,670 --> 00:33:52,230
You'll finish weighing that heart?

472
00:33:54,460 --> 00:33:57,140
That makes you the only person south of the Twins who does.

473
00:34:00,400 --> 00:34:02,550
We're not like the people south of the Twins.

474
00:34:03,400 --> 00:34:05,660
And we're not like the people north of the Twins.

475
00:34:07,730 --> 00:34:11,680
In the Citadel, we lead different lives for different reasons.

476
00:34:13,510 --> 00:34:16,240
We are this world's memory, Samwell Tarly.

477
00:34:16,240 --> 00:34:18,940
Without us, men would be little better than dogs.

478
00:34:19,320 --> 00:34:21,400
Don't remember any meal but the last,

479
00:34:21,410 --> 00:34:23,710
can't see forward to any but the next.

480
00:34:24,610 --> 00:34:26,120
And every time you leave the house and shut the door,

481
00:34:26,130 --> 00:34:28,040
they howl like you're gone forever.

482
00:34:29,360 --> 00:34:31,560
When Robert's Rebellion was raging,

483
00:34:32,370 --> 00:34:34,030
people thought the end was near.

484
00:34:34,030 --> 00:34:37,150
The end of the Targaryen dynasty. "How will we survive?"

485
00:34:37,180 --> 00:34:40,080
When Aegon Targaryen turned his eye westward

486
00:34:40,600 --> 00:34:42,400
and flew his dragons to Blackwater Rush,

487
00:34:42,400 --> 00:34:44,660
"The end is near! How will we survive?"

488
00:34:44,820 --> 00:34:47,350
And thousands of years before that, during the Long Night,

489
00:34:47,350 --> 00:34:49,390
we can forgive them for thinking it truly was the end.

490
00:34:49,390 --> 00:34:52,320
But it wasn't. None of it was.

491
00:34:54,000 --> 00:34:56,360
The Wall has stood through it all.

492
00:34:57,860 --> 00:35:00,630
And every winter that ever came has ended.

493
00:35:09,110 --> 00:35:10,980
Be a good lad. Clean this up.

494
00:36:01,490 --> 00:36:02,400
Nope.

495
00:36:13,740 --> 00:36:14,780
Nope.

496
00:36:27,440 --> 00:36:29,350
You're a lucky man.

497
00:36:34,120 --> 00:36:36,660
I've heard she beat the Hound in single combat.

498
00:36:41,420 --> 00:36:43,190
She's a very impressive woman.

499
00:36:44,320 --> 00:36:46,380
What do you want, Lord Baelish?

500
00:36:49,840 --> 00:36:51,320
I want you to be happy.

501
00:36:52,560 --> 00:36:54,120
I want you to be safe.

502
00:36:54,120 --> 00:36:55,560
I am safe.

503
00:36:55,760 --> 00:36:57,930
I'm at home, surrounded by friends.

504
00:36:58,950 --> 00:37:01,760
I have Brienne to protect me from anyone who would harm me.

505
00:37:05,890 --> 00:37:07,200
What about happy?

506
00:37:10,480 --> 00:37:11,840
Why aren't you happy?

507
00:37:12,370 --> 00:37:14,470
What do you want that you do not have?

508
00:37:14,470 --> 00:37:17,000
At the moment, peace and quiet.

509
00:37:22,260 --> 00:37:25,170
No need to seize the last word, Lord Baelish.

510
00:37:25,360 --> 00:37:27,450
I'll assume it was something clever.

511
00:37:30,000 --> 00:37:31,460
My lady.

512
00:37:31,980 --> 00:37:33,050
My lady.

513
00:37:43,630 --> 00:37:45,230
Why is he still here?

514
00:37:46,230 --> 00:37:47,660
We need his men.

515
00:37:48,320 --> 00:37:49,540
Without the Vale,

516
00:37:49,540 --> 00:37:51,440
Ramsay Bolton would still hold this castle.

517
00:37:52,970 --> 00:37:54,620
Littlefinger saved us.

518
00:37:58,750 --> 00:38:00,100
He wants something.

519
00:38:02,180 --> 00:38:04,460
I know exactly what he wants.

520
00:38:09,670 --> 00:38:12,800
*He rode through the streets of the city*

521
00:38:13,170 --> 00:38:16,210
*Down from his hill on high*

522
00:38:16,290 --> 00:38:19,500
*O'er the winds and the steps and the cobbles*

523
00:38:19,810 --> 00:38:22,760
*He rode to a woman's sigh*

524
00:38:23,330 --> 00:38:26,450
*For she was his secret treasure*

525
00:38:26,560 --> 00:38:29,530
*She was his shame and his bliss*

526
00:38:29,970 --> 00:38:32,880
*And a chain and a keep are nothing*

527
00:38:32,880 --> 00:38:35,550
*Compared to a woman's kiss*

528
00:38:35,550 --> 00:38:38,910
*For hands of gold are always cold*

529
00:38:38,910 --> 00:38:41,980
*But a woman's hands are warm*

530
00:38:42,260 --> 00:38:45,520
*For hands of gold are always cold*

531
00:38:45,520 --> 00:38:48,520
*But a woman's hands are…*

532
00:38:49,920 --> 00:38:51,070
That's a pretty song.

533
00:38:51,390 --> 00:38:52,600
I've never heard it before.

534
00:38:52,600 --> 00:38:53,630
It's a new one.

535
00:38:53,800 --> 00:38:56,230
Are you hungry? We've got some rabbit.

536
00:38:57,000 --> 00:38:58,320
I don't want to steal your food.

537
00:38:58,320 --> 00:39:00,160
You're not stealing, we're offering.

538
00:39:00,900 --> 00:39:02,820
Come on, it's gonna be a cold night.

539
00:39:31,590 --> 00:39:32,730
You heading south?

540
00:39:33,050 --> 00:39:34,050
King's Landing.

541
00:39:35,200 --> 00:39:36,190
Poor girl.

542
00:39:37,490 --> 00:39:38,700
Not so bad, is it?

543
00:39:40,170 --> 00:39:41,940
Depends on your taste, I guess.

544
00:39:42,130 --> 00:39:43,020
If you like your streets covered

545
00:39:43,030 --> 00:39:45,600
in shit and pig's blood, it's the town for you.

546
00:39:46,120 --> 00:39:48,340
All my life, I wanted to see the Red Keep,

547
00:39:48,370 --> 00:39:50,630
the Sept of Baelor, the Dragonpit.

548
00:39:50,630 --> 00:39:52,310
Then when I finally make it,

549
00:39:52,310 --> 00:39:54,290
they wouldn't let me within a mile of the Red Keep,

550
00:39:54,290 --> 00:39:56,450
the Sept of Baelor's blown to hell,

551
00:39:56,540 --> 00:39:58,920
and the Dragonpit is a damn ruin.

552
00:39:58,920 --> 00:40:00,270
The people who live there,

553
00:40:00,320 --> 00:40:01,150
they'd skin you alive if

554
00:40:01,160 --> 00:40:03,040
they could make two coppers off your hide.

555
00:40:03,050 --> 00:40:04,910
Worst place in the world.

556
00:40:05,450 --> 00:40:07,280
What are you doing in the Riverlands?

557
00:40:07,750 --> 00:40:10,310
There's been some trouble with the Freys up at the Twins,

558
00:40:10,310 --> 00:40:13,910
so we're part of the army that's been sent to keep the peace.

559
00:40:16,680 --> 00:40:19,870
Here you go. Guests first.

560
00:40:19,870 --> 00:40:21,570
Oh, no, I couldn't. You don't have enough.

561
00:40:21,570 --> 00:40:24,100
My mother always told me to be kind to strangers.

562
00:40:24,100 --> 00:40:25,950
Strangers will be kind to you.

563
00:40:38,750 --> 00:40:40,320
You're a long way from home.

564
00:40:40,580 --> 00:40:42,570
I'm sure you've had some adventures, though.

565
00:40:42,570 --> 00:40:45,520
Yeah, endless adventures.

566
00:40:45,730 --> 00:40:48,270
They'll be singing about us for a thousand years.

567
00:40:48,270 --> 00:40:51,890
The truth is when we left home, we couldn't wait to get away.

568
00:40:51,890 --> 00:40:54,210
But now we've been gone a while, we can't wait to get home.

569
00:40:54,210 --> 00:40:57,240
I just think about my dad out there on his boat all alone.

570
00:40:58,510 --> 00:41:00,140
I ought to be out there with him.

571
00:41:01,440 --> 00:41:03,450
My wife just had our first baby.

572
00:41:03,450 --> 00:41:05,700
- Boy or girl? - Oh, who knows?

573
00:41:05,700 --> 00:41:08,380
You think soldiers get ravens with news from home?

574
00:41:11,650 --> 00:41:14,460
- I hope it's a girl. - Why?

575
00:41:14,460 --> 00:41:17,450
Girls take care of their papas when their papas grow old.

576
00:41:17,450 --> 00:41:20,090
Boys just go off to fight in someone else's wars.

577
00:41:22,240 --> 00:41:24,000
Are you old enough to drink?

578
00:41:39,360 --> 00:41:41,150
It's blackberry wine.

579
00:41:41,160 --> 00:41:42,960
I made it myself.

580
00:41:44,150 --> 00:41:45,380
It's really good.

581
00:41:47,480 --> 00:41:51,290
So, why is a nice girl on her own heading to King's Landing?

582
00:41:58,290 --> 00:41:59,890
I'm going to kill the queen.

583
00:42:21,580 --> 00:42:23,670
Bad night to be outdoors.

584
00:42:23,670 --> 00:42:27,230
You've got real powerful magic to figure that out.

585
00:42:27,570 --> 00:42:30,470
Did the Lord of Light whisper that in your ear?

586
00:42:30,560 --> 00:42:33,730
"It's snowing, Thoros. It's windy.

587
00:42:33,730 --> 00:42:36,030
It's gonna be a cold night."

588
00:42:36,680 --> 00:42:39,820
You're a grouchy old bear, aren't you, Clegane?

589
00:42:40,390 --> 00:42:41,880
You want some rum?

590
00:42:42,120 --> 00:42:44,520
Don't like that shit. It's too sweet.

591
00:42:45,170 --> 00:42:48,120
Why are you always in such a foul mood?

592
00:42:49,470 --> 00:42:51,500
Experience.

593
00:42:56,030 --> 00:42:58,560
This seems like a good place to spend the night.

594
00:43:00,810 --> 00:43:03,130
These people don't want us here.

595
00:43:03,130 --> 00:43:06,120
Seems deserted to me. No livestock.

596
00:43:06,130 --> 00:43:08,200
No smoke coming from the chimney.

597
00:43:27,640 --> 00:43:29,380
I don't like the look of it.

598
00:43:29,670 --> 00:43:32,170
For a big, hard man, you scare easy.

599
00:43:32,170 --> 00:43:34,600
I'll tell you what doesn't scare me--

600
00:43:34,760 --> 00:43:36,820
bald cocksuckers like you.

601
00:43:36,830 --> 00:43:39,840
You think you're fooling anyone with that top knot?

602
00:43:40,160 --> 00:43:41,740
Bald cunt.

603
00:43:43,390 --> 00:43:44,500
Come on.

604
00:43:44,910 --> 00:43:47,350
Maybe they've got some ale hidden away.

605
00:43:48,320 --> 00:43:49,850
They don't.

606
00:43:52,730 --> 00:43:54,300
See if there's a larder.

607
00:43:54,300 --> 00:43:56,300
They always leave something behind.

608
00:44:37,950 --> 00:44:40,050
How do you think it ended for them?

609
00:44:40,670 --> 00:44:42,270
With death.

610
00:44:42,400 --> 00:44:44,620
Girl died in her father's arms.

611
00:44:45,060 --> 00:44:48,030
Both of them covered in blood and a knife at their feet.

612
00:44:50,230 --> 00:44:51,860
I'd say they were starving.

613
00:44:51,860 --> 00:44:54,010
And rather than let his little girl suffer,

614
00:44:54,010 --> 00:44:55,930
he ended it for both of them.

615
00:44:56,610 --> 00:44:58,020
Doesn't matter now.

616
00:44:58,020 --> 00:45:01,320
No, doesn't matter now.

617
00:45:14,650 --> 00:45:17,310
I've known you a long time, Dondarrion.

618
00:45:17,330 --> 00:45:18,560
Aye.

619
00:45:18,570 --> 00:45:22,450
I think the first time we met was at that tournament--

620
00:45:22,450 --> 00:45:26,470
And I always thought you were dull as dirt.

621
00:45:26,870 --> 00:45:28,360
You're not bad.

622
00:45:28,630 --> 00:45:30,340
I don't hate you.

623
00:45:30,400 --> 00:45:32,520
Don't like you, but you're not bad.

624
00:45:32,520 --> 00:45:34,100
Thank you, Clegane.

625
00:45:34,430 --> 00:45:35,890
That warms the heart.

626
00:45:35,890 --> 00:45:38,810
But there's nothing special about you.

627
00:45:39,220 --> 00:45:40,970
You're right about that.

628
00:45:40,970 --> 00:45:44,480
So why does the Lord of Light keep bringing you back?

629
00:45:44,960 --> 00:45:47,160
I've met better men than you,

630
00:45:47,160 --> 00:45:51,860
and they've been hanged from crossbeams, or beheaded,

631
00:45:52,250 --> 00:45:56,110
or just shat themselves to death in a field somewhere.

632
00:45:57,020 --> 00:45:59,000
None of them came back.

633
00:46:00,390 --> 00:46:01,790
So, why you?

634
00:46:01,830 --> 00:46:04,200
You think I don't ask myself that?

635
00:46:04,470 --> 00:46:06,650
Every hour of every day?

636
00:46:07,610 --> 00:46:09,260
Why am I here?

637
00:46:10,650 --> 00:46:12,430
What am I supposed to do?

638
00:46:12,430 --> 00:46:14,390
What does the Lord see in me?

639
00:46:16,200 --> 00:46:17,610
And?

640
00:46:19,260 --> 00:46:20,800
I don't know.

641
00:46:21,950 --> 00:46:23,970
I don't understand our Lord.

642
00:46:23,970 --> 00:46:25,800
Your Lord.

643
00:46:25,840 --> 00:46:27,820
I don't know what He wants from me.

644
00:46:27,910 --> 00:46:32,300
I only know that He wants me alive.

645
00:46:32,300 --> 00:46:33,830
If he's so all-powerful,

646
00:46:33,840 --> 00:46:36,940
why doesn't he just tell you what the fuck he wants?

647
00:46:38,490 --> 00:46:39,780
Clegane.

648
00:46:40,570 --> 00:46:42,040
Come over here.

649
00:46:44,300 --> 00:46:46,620
Don't worry. The fire won't bite.

650
00:46:47,730 --> 00:46:49,590
I want to show you something.

651
00:46:50,340 --> 00:46:54,250
It's my fucking luck I end up with a band of fire worshippers.

652
00:46:54,500 --> 00:46:55,890
Aye.

653
00:46:56,090 --> 00:46:58,730
Almost seems like divine justice.

654
00:46:58,730 --> 00:47:00,830
There's no divine justice, you dumb cunt.

655
00:47:00,830 --> 00:47:02,860
If there was, you'd be dead...

656
00:47:03,910 --> 00:47:06,390
and that girl would be alive.

657
00:47:12,470 --> 00:47:15,400
- What do you want? - Look into the flames.

658
00:47:15,400 --> 00:47:18,200
I don't want to look in the damn flames.

659
00:47:18,330 --> 00:47:21,360
You saw me bring him back from the dead after you cut him down.

660
00:47:22,650 --> 00:47:25,120
Don't you want to know what gave me the power?

661
00:47:25,120 --> 00:47:28,410
I keep asking and no one wants to tell me.

662
00:47:28,500 --> 00:47:30,150
We can't tell you.

663
00:47:30,170 --> 00:47:32,310
Only the fire can tell you.

664
00:47:44,780 --> 00:47:46,270
What do you see?

665
00:47:47,900 --> 00:47:49,570
Logs burning.

666
00:47:50,140 --> 00:47:51,670
Keep looking.

667
00:47:57,070 --> 00:47:58,580
What do you see?

668
00:48:07,780 --> 00:48:09,240
Ice.

669
00:48:10,450 --> 00:48:12,550
A wall of ice.

670
00:48:14,920 --> 00:48:16,480
The Wall.

671
00:48:19,020 --> 00:48:20,100
What else?

672
00:48:20,110 --> 00:48:24,440
It's where the Wall meets the sea.

673
00:48:25,210 --> 00:48:27,400
There's a castle there.

674
00:48:34,800 --> 00:48:36,990
There's a mountain.

675
00:48:37,250 --> 00:48:39,300
Looks like an arrowhead.

676
00:48:42,540 --> 00:48:45,020
The dead are marching past.

677
00:48:49,490 --> 00:48:51,160
Thousands of them.

678
00:48:57,500 --> 00:48:59,460
Do you believe me now, Clegane?

679
00:49:00,600 --> 00:49:02,750
Do you believe we're here for a reason?

680
00:49:34,230 --> 00:49:36,490
What the hell are you doing, Clegane?

681
00:49:39,250 --> 00:49:40,790
Burying the dead.

682
00:49:53,980 --> 00:49:55,760
You knew these people.

683
00:49:56,110 --> 00:49:57,870
Not really.

684
00:50:58,190 --> 00:51:01,410
We ask the Father to judge us with mercy.

685
00:51:02,070 --> 00:51:04,960
We ask the Mother to...

686
00:51:07,840 --> 00:51:10,360
Fuck it, I don't remember the rest.

687
00:51:16,420 --> 00:51:18,090
I'm sorry you're dead.

688
00:51:19,440 --> 00:51:21,350
You deserved better.

689
00:51:22,390 --> 00:51:24,060
Both of you.

690
00:51:54,310 --> 00:51:55,580
Mom.

691
00:51:55,630 --> 00:51:57,830
You should really sleep, Sam.

692
00:51:58,680 --> 00:52:00,330
The dead don't.

693
00:52:09,210 --> 00:52:12,850
"Legends of the Long Night."

694
00:52:14,520 --> 00:52:17,710
The Targaryens used dragonglass to decorate their weapons

695
00:52:17,710 --> 00:52:20,680
without even knowing what the First Men used it for.

696
00:52:37,590 --> 00:52:38,950
What is it?

697
00:52:40,290 --> 00:52:42,430
It's a map of Dragonstone.

698
00:52:42,430 --> 00:52:44,700
The Targaryens built their first stronghold there

699
00:52:44,700 --> 00:52:46,590
when they invaded Westeros.

700
00:52:48,990 --> 00:52:50,870
That's dragonglass?

701
00:52:50,870 --> 00:52:52,520
A mountain of it.

702
00:52:52,580 --> 00:52:53,850
Beneath the ground.

703
00:52:53,850 --> 00:52:56,070
Stannis told me, but I didn't think...

704
00:52:56,660 --> 00:53:00,010
This is important. Jon needs to know.

705
00:53:52,930 --> 00:53:54,490
Has she come yet?

706
00:53:54,850 --> 00:53:56,060
Who?

707
00:53:56,560 --> 00:53:58,270
The Dragon Queen.

708
00:53:58,850 --> 00:54:00,790
Daenerys Stormborn.

709
00:54:02,560 --> 00:54:04,030
Haven't heard anything.

710
00:59:43,760 --> 00:59:45,180
Shall we begin?

711
01:01:06,920 --> 01:01:08,950
A Targaryen cannot be trusted.

713
01:01:09,920 --> 01:01:12,420
The Mad King's daughter will destroy the realm.

714
01:01:12,420 --> 01:01:15,740
We have an army of fleets and three dragons.

715
01:01:15,770 --> 01:01:18,040
We should hit King's Landing now.

